Ready?
好了嗎？ 好了
Hi,it's Rachel and Phoebe's. Please...
嗨… 這是…瑞秋… 和…菲比的家 請…
-Leave.. -Leave.
在嗶聲後… 在嗶聲後…
But I just said "leave."
那個我說過了
I know because you have all the good words.
我知道，因為你都分到好的字
What do I get? I get "it's," "and." Oh,I'm sorry, I have "a." Forget it.
而我呢？「這是」、「和」 還有「留言」…我不要
-That's silly. -All right. So let's switch.
菲比，別鬧了 好，那我們交換
No,I have all the good words.
不要，我都分到好的字
Okay,fine,fine. We can switch.
好吧，我們交換
- Hi... -everybody...
嗨… 大家好
-It's... -Rachel...
這是… 瑞秋…
-and... -Phoebe's.
和… 菲比的家
Wait. How did you do that?
請…慢著，你是怎麼弄的？
What?
什麼？
Oh,you're no ordinary roommate, are you?
你不是普通角色對吧？
This is gonna be interesting.
這下有好戲可看了
Can we finish this later? I'm going running before it gets dark.
菲比，待會再錄好嗎？ 我想在天黑前去慢跑
-Why don't you come with me? -Really?
你也一起來嘛 真的？
It'll be fun! We'll run in the park. It'll be our roommate-bonding thing.
對，一定很好玩，去公園跑步 當做室友間第一次聯絡感情
Okay,let's go running!
好，我們去跑步
-There's cute guys there. -Let's run towards them!
而且那裡有帥哥 那就往他們跑過去
Wait just one more second.
你等我一下
Hi,it's Phoebe and Rachel's. Please leave a message. Thanks!
嗨，這是瑞秋和菲比的家 請在嗶聲後留言，謝謝
Wait a minute. You took all the words!
等等，你都講完了
You've met your match, Rachel Greene!
你遇到對手了，瑞秋葛林
The One Where Phoebe Runs
本集播出： 「喬伊的煩惱」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
I just finished this fascinating book.
我剛看完一本很棒的書
By the year 2030, there'll be computers...
到了2030年，有些電腦
that can carry out the same amount of functions as a human brain.
能執行跟人腦一樣多的功能
So,theoretically, you could download...
所以理論上你可以下載
your thoughts and memories into this computer...
你的思想記憶到這種電腦上
and live forever as a machine.
然後以機器的形態長生不死
And I just realized I can sleep with my eyes open.
我剛發現我能睜著眼睛睡覺
Honey,it was a great idea, nailing the boxes to the floor.
把箱子釘在地上真是聰明
-I didn't nail the boxes to the floor. -So you can move them!
我沒把箱子釘在地上 所以你可以搬走羅
And while I'm doing that, Ross has a great computer story for you.
可以，我這就搬 羅斯有個很好聽的電腦故事
Hey,everybody! I'd like you to meet Janine.
大家好，這是吉寧
She's gonna be my new roommate!
她是我的新室友
你好
And she's gonna live with me!
她要來跟我住
It's nice to meet you. Janine...?
很高興認識你，吉寧…
Le Croix.
勒誇，吉寧勒誇
I didn't know that. What a pretty last name.
我都不知道，好好聽的姓
So where are you from?
你是哪裡人？
Australia. I just moved here.
奧洲人，2星期前剛到
From the land down under?
來自南半球？
I didn't know that either!
這個我也不知道
So what do you do?
你做哪一行？
-I'm a dancer. -You're a dancer?
我是個舞者 你是個舞者？
She's a dancer!
她是個舞者
I think I'll go unpack.
我要去整理東西了 我幫你開門
喬伊
Did you interview her before you asked her to move in?
你叫她搬來之前有先面試嗎？
Of course!
當然有
What did you ask her?
你到底問了什麼？
When can you move in?
「你什麼時候可以搬來？」
Thank you for bringing her into our lives.
謝謝你把她帶到我們身邊
Unbelievable.
難以置信
Down,boy.
別太興奮
Oh,no,no,no. She's not my type. Not for me,she's not my type. She's too..
她不是我喜歡的型，她太…
Beautiful,tall,sexy, showing her stomach?
美麗、高挑、性感、露肚臍？
Look at all the boxes!
你看這堆箱子
I cannot wait to ask her out.
我好想趕快約她
Wait a minute. You can't. She's your roommate.
喬伊，你不能約她 她是你的室友
It'll be too complicated.
那樣會太複雜
Yeah,don't do it.
沒錯，千萬不要
I mean,if you date her, then I can't date her.
你約了她，我就不能約她了
What if you started going out with her and it didn't work out?
要是你跟她交往又分手呢？
That's when I make my move.
那就該我行動了
Remember when you broke up with Donna...
你之前跟一個唐娜交往 後來分手
how horrible it was when you bumped into her at the supermarket?
記得你們在超市巧遇的尷尬嗎
Oh,God,yeah.
沒錯
Now imagine you live at the supermarket.
想像你住在超市裡
Okay!
好啊
不是
You're right! I don't want that. I can't date her.
你說得對，那樣很不好 我不能約她
You'd better watch the flirting too, because it could be trouble.
最好也別跟她調情 住得這麼近可能會出事
Well,that's gonna be tough, Mon.
太難了
It's hard for me to be around an attractive woman and not flirt.
畢竟美女當前 我很難不打情罵俏
You're around me all the time, and you don't flirt.
我老是在你面前，你也沒怎樣
A little sad about that, sweetie?
有點難過是吧？
I have to tie my shoes, so you go ahead. I'll catch up.
我要綁鞋帶，你先跑，我就來 好
Come on, that's not running! Let's go!
拜託，那哪叫跑步，快點
I'm telling you,when she runs...
我是說真的，她跑步的時候
she looks like Kermit the Frog...
就像大嘴蛙...
and the Six Million Dollar Man.
和生化機器人合體
Monica had such a crush on him.
摩妮卡以前好喜歡他
She used to kiss his poster every night before she went to bed.
她睡覺之前都會親他的海報
I used to do that too!
我也會
Did you also have his album, "It's Not Easy Being Green"?
你有他的專輯 「全身綠色的煩惱」 嗎？
Oh,Mon.
摩妮卡…
So Phoebe runs weird, huh?
所以菲比的姿勢很怪？
Yeah. And I know she'll want to run again.
對，而且她還會想再去跑
I don't know how to get out of it. I mean,I live with her.
我躲不掉，我跟她住在一起
Why don't you be straight with her? Tell her the truth.
你就實話實說嘛
You're right. I should just tell her the truth.
你說得對，我應該跟她直說
Phoebe, Monica tripped me. I don't think I can ever run again,ever!
菲比，摩妮卡把我絆倒 我再也不能跑步了
But we were having so much fun. All those cute guys were checking us out.
但是我們跑得好開心 那些帥哥都在看我們
I know. They were definitely staring.
就是啊，他們都瞪著我們看
Why? Why would you do that?
你為什麼要絆倒她？
I don't know.
我不知道
Rachel,I'm sorry I hurt your ankles.
瑞秋，抱歉害你兩個腳踝受傷
-Ankle. -We'll see.
只有一個 等著瞧
Okay. I am officially unpacked.
好，東西都拿出來了
Thanks for helping me,man.
多謝幫忙
Joe?
喬伊？
Well,I guess Joey went home.
看來他回家了
And look,there is still one box I have to unpack.
看，還有一個箱子沒拆
I got you!
你被騙了
Oh,my God, you almost gave me a heart attack.
天哪，我差點被嚇出心臟病
It was so hard not to laugh.
我憋笑憋得好辛苦
Hey, the place looks great.
很像回事嘛
Not bad,right?
不賴吧？
Monica's working late, so I'm gonna make this place spotless.
摩妮卡今天要加班 我要把這裡打掃得一塵不染
You know what else I'll do?
還有還有
I'm gonna go downstairs and get her some flowers.
我還要下樓去買花送她
Who wouldn't want to live with me?
誰會不想跟我住？
I don't.
我不想
No,I want to live with the super-hot Australian dancer!
我想跟性感的奧洲舞者住
How's that going? Are you okay with the not-flirting thing?
情況如何？你能不打情罵俏嗎
So far. But it's tough.
目前還可以，但是好累
I've got this built-up flirting energy, and I don't know how to get rid of it.
我的調情能量一直累積 無處發洩
How you doing?
你好嗎？
Get out!
滾啦
Oh,man!
天哪
Sorry. There's just more room out here.
抱歉，客廳比較寬
No,you just reminded me that I have to do my stretches too.
不是，我只是想到 我也該拉拉筋了
Why don't you try to be...?
你應該…
-What's wrong? -Nothing.
怎麼了？ 沒事
I didn't want you to touch me...
你不要碰我
because I'm all sweaty from the workout.
我拉筋拉得全身是汗
I'm gonna hit the shower.
我去洗個澡
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Sorry about that stuff hanging in there.
抱歉在浴室晾衣服
It's just my thongs are too delicate for the dryer.
我的丁字褲很嬌貴，不能烘乾
Oh,yeah,it's me.
沒錯，是我
I saw you grab your running shoes this morning and sneak out.
我看到你抄了慢跑鞋溜出來
You lied so you could run by yourself.
你騙我好自己跑步
No,Phoebe,no. I was....
不是，我沒有 我是…
I was actually just checking...
我只是跑跑看…
to see...
if I could run. And I can!
看我能不能跑，結果可以
Please,I'm not an idiot.
拜託，我又不是白癡
No,wait. Phoebe?
等等，菲比
Wow. Couples who live together do start to look alike.
同居真的會讓人越來越像
I am working right now. So say what you have to say and leave me alone!
我在忙，有話快說，有屁快放
Sound alike too.
口氣也很像
So,Mondler....
摩德…
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
What does it look like? I am cleaning.
你說呢？我在打掃
Did you get Monica's authorization to move all her stuff?
你動她的東西有經過她同意嗎
I don't need that. I'll put everything back.
沒必要，我會把東西都放回去
Put it back exactly where you found it?
完全恢復原狀嗎？
Yes. I'm gonna put it back exactly where I found it.
當然是完全恢復原狀
First of all, that attitude is not helping.
這種態度對你沒有幫助
She won't care if I put her stuff back in the same stupid place.
她才不會在乎有沒有恢復原狀
Hello? Did you just meet Monica?
你是剛認識摩妮卡嗎？
She'll recognize that I did a nice thing...
她會認同我的體帖...
and appreciate it.
並感到窩心
Actually,this will work out well.
其實這樣也蠻好的
Because when you move back with Joey...
等你必須搬回去跟喬伊住
Joey's hot new roommate can come live with me.
喬伊的新室友就可以來跟我住
Oh,I see. You're trying to freak me out.
我懂了，你想嚇我
Chandler, Monica is really weird about this kind of stuff, all right?
錢德，摩妮卡對這種事有怪癖
Believe me,I lived with her for 16 years. She's going to freak out.
相信我，我跟她住了16年 她會捉狂
Oh,my God. She's going to sit on you.
天哪，她會壓在你身上
That probably won't hurt as much anymore.
不過她現在瘦了
No,she is not. I'll prove it to you.
她才不會，我證明給你看
I'll call her right now.
我現在就打給她
Phone's done.
電話擦好了
-Hey,Mon. How's it going? -Terrible.
摩妮卡，你好嗎？ 爛透了
If I want something done right, I have to do it myself.
什麼事都得我自己來
Other people just wreck stuff.
其他人只會搞砸
I think I might kill someone tonight.
我今晚可能會殺人
Come on, it can't be that bad.
別這樣，沒那麼糟吧
The only thing getting me through...
是非常糟，想到快見到你了
is knowing I'll see you soon.
我才撐得下去
I might even try to get out of here early.
我搞不好會設法早退 不要…
It sounds like they need you there.
餐廳似乎很需要你
-You're just hanging out with Ross? -It's all good! Okay,bye!
你跟羅斯在一起嗎？ 一切都很好，再見
She's gonna kill me.
她會宰了我
The phone was facing the other way.
電話放反了
And that goes back up there.
相框應該擺在上面
This is good. This is under control. We should start with the big stuff.
好，一切都在掌握中 我們從大型傢俱復原起
That'll be the easiest. Let's start with the couch.
那樣比較簡單 先搬沙發
I got it.
我沒問題
That doesn't look right.
位置好像不對
What are you talking about? The couch is in line with the carpet.
什麼意思？ 沙發剛好跟毯子對齊
Then I can just walk over here and casually put my feet up on....
我可以走到這邊 輕鬆的把腳翹在…
Okay, here's what we do.
好
We move the couch closer to the coffee table.
那就把沙發往咖啡桌那邊推
But then the back of the couch won't line up with the carpet.
那沙發的背後 就不會跟毯子邊緣對齊了
Well,we'll just move the coffee table...
那就把咖啡桌...
closer to the couch.
往沙發那邊推
But then the coffee table won't be centered in the seating area.
那咖啡桌就不在座位區正中央了
But the coffee table doesn't match the table!
那咖啡桌就…羅斯
Look, what am I gonna do?
我該怎麼辦？
I'm not flirting, but I'm drawing her to me like a moth to a flame!
我不調情，卻還是吸引著她 就像火吸引著飛蛾
What the hell's going on over here?
這裡是怎麼了？
Monica's gonna kill you!
摩妮卡會宰了你
I need your help.
我需要你們的幫忙
I have to do something to repel this woman.
我得想辦法把這個女人嚇跑
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
等等
You guys repel women all the time!
你們最會把女人嚇跑了
Hey, I've been married three times.
我可是結過三次婚
No, I've seen it happen.
不，我親眼見識過
You get a rapport going with a woman, but somehow you manage to kill it.
你們跟女人交往得好好的 最後卻總是能搞砸
Time after time after time after time.
一次一次又一次
What's your secret?
你們的秘訣是什麼？
We do not repel women,okay?
我們並不會把女人嚇跑
That is completely untrue.
完全沒有這回事
Oh, yes, we do, my man.
我們確實會
Remember when we went to a dance...
記不記得大學參加春季舞會
and you walked up to that girl you liked and talked...
你走向看對眼的女生
about the lrish potato famine?
卻大談愛爾蘭馬鈴薯饑荒？
What about you? You weren't so hot either.
那你呢？你當年也沒那麼酷
After everything he said, he'd go..
他每次說完話都會...
Monica doesn't like that either. I should stop doing that.
摩妮卡也不喜歡 也許我應該改掉
Girls don't like it when I start talking about science.
對了，女生不喜歡我聊科學
That's not specific to girls.
不只是女生
This is great. What else?
太好了，還有呢？
They don't like you correcting their grammar.
她們不喜歡你糾正她們的文法
And they don't like it when you explain why your jokes are funny.
她們不喜歡你解釋 你的笑話哪裡好笑
They don't like it when you keep asking them if they like you.
她們不喜歡你一直問她們 喜不喜歡你
-Man,I am so lucky I have Monica. -I'm never gonna find love again.
天哪，幸好我有摩妮卡 我再也別想談戀愛了
-Can I talk to you for a second? -Sure.
菲比，可以跟你談一談嗎？ 好啊
Phoebe,I just wanted to say I'm sorry,okay?
菲比，我只是想跟你道歉
I handled the situation horribly.
我處理得很差
And I should not have lied to you.
而且我不該騙你
So what should you have done?
那你應該怎樣？
I should have told you the truth.
我應該跟你說實話
Which is?
而實話是…
Well,the reason I didn't want to go running with you is...
我之所以不想跟你跑步
because...
是因為…
the way that you run is just a little....
你跑步的姿勢有點…
-So? -It's embarrassing.
所以呢？ 很尷尬
People were looking at us like we were crazy.
別人都當我們是瘋子
-Why do you care? -Because they're people!
你幹嘛在意？ 因為他們是人
People you don't know and will never see again.
你不認識也不會再見到的人
Yes,but still they are people...
但他們依舊是人
with eyes.
有眼睛
I didn't get embarrassed running next to Miss....
我就不怕跟喘氣小姐跑步
But okay.
但是好吧
I can see why running with me would be embarrassing to you.
難怪你會覺得 跟我跑步很尷尬
Okay. You're uptight.
你很緊張
What? I am not uptight.
我哪有緊張
I am not uptight,man.
我才不緊張，老兄
That's okay. I'm not judging you. That's just who you are.
沒關係，我不是在批評你 你就是這樣
I'm more free,you know. I run like I did when I was a kid...
我就比較自由 我從小就這樣跑
because that's the only way it's fun, you know?
因為這樣才好玩
Didn't you ever run so fast you thought your legs would fall off...
你從來沒有往前衝到 腿好像快斷了嗎？
Like when you were running towards the swings or running away from Satan?
例如要跑去玩蕩鞦韆 或是在躲魔鬼時？
The neighbor's dog.
鄰居的狗
Is this in the right place?
這盞燈沒擺錯吧？
Who cares? I repel women.
管他的，我會把女人嚇跑
You can't come in here!
不行！你不能進來
Ross is naked!
羅斯光著身體
什麼？
I couldn't say I was naked, because she's allowed to see me naked.
我不能說我光著身體 她可以看我光著身體
Why does anyone have to be naked?
為什麼一定要有人光著身體？
Why is Ross naked?
羅斯為什麼光著身體？
I had to show Chandler something.
我要給錢德看一個東西
Naked?
光著身體看？
I guess I have...
對，我好像有...
a "guy" problem.
男人病
Is it the same thing Chandler had?
跟錢德的一樣嗎？
We'll get everything squared away, and you can come back later!
待會再回來 我們搞定了你再回來
There's still some of Chandler's medicine in the bathroom.
好，浴室洗手台底下 還有錢德的藥
-Bye. -Bye!
再見
Thank God.
謝天謝地
Dude, what'd you have?
你有什麼病？
We have no time, okay? We must focus.
沒時間了，我們必須專心
We've got to get everything back into its original place.
我們得把一切恢復原狀
The photo album!
相簿
There were millions of pictures of the apartment in the photo album.
相簿裡有一大堆這裡的照片
We just match everything to the pictures!
我們可以拿照片來對
That's perfect! That's brilliant!
太好了，好主意
What'd you have?
說真的，你有什麼病？
I've got some beer for you.
喬伊，我幫你買了啤酒
Don't you mean "for whom"?
是「幫誰」吧
Sure.
好
I was gonna order some pizza. You wanna share one?
我正想叫披薩，你要一起吃嗎
Pizza? It's not like I never had that before.
披薩，我又不是沒吃過
Is something wrong?
有什麼問題嗎？
Yeah. I'm depressed about that Irish potato famine.
愛爾蘭馬鈴薯饑荒令我很沮喪
No,I mean with me. Because you seem to be acting really weird around me.
我是指對我 你對我的態度總是怪怪的
All right,all right.
好吧
Let's just get this out in the open, okay?
我就明說了
You're hot.
你很火辣
I'm lovable.
我很俊俏
Clearly,there's a vibe going on between us.
我們兩個顯然很有感覺
But we're roommates...
但我們是室友
and it's a huge mistake for us to continue down this road.
我們不能走上這條路
Imagine living in a supermarket...
想像你住在超市裡
and you'll understand.
這樣你就懂了
Okay? So the question is, what do we do?
所以我們該怎麼辦？
There isn't anything to do.
不怎麼辦
I think you're really sweet.
我覺得你人很好
But I'm not interested in you like that.
但是我對你沒興趣
No,I mean....
不是…
You're a nice guy, and I'm happy to be your roommate and your friend.
你人真的很好 我很高興能當你的室友和朋友
I'm just,you know,I just...
只是...只是...
don't feel that way about you.
我對你沒有那種感覺
I see what happened.
我知道了
It's because I was trying to repel you.
因為我一直想把你嚇跑
Right? Believe me,you'd feel a lot different if I turned it on.
相信我，等我一放電 情況就不同了
-I don't think so. -Oh,I do.
應該不會 絕對會
How you doing?
你好嗎？
I'm okay.
我很好
What?
什麼？
怎樣？
Oh,dear God!
我的天哪
I'm so sorry. You're right. This feels great!
對不起，你說得對，感覺好爽
And you don't care if people stare. It's only a second. Then you're gone!
對吧？你不會在意別人的目光 才幾秒鐘你就跑不見了
It's amazing! I feel so free and so graceful!
沒錯，感覺真的好棒 我覺得好自由好優雅
Watch out for the horse.
小心那匹馬…
Can I come in now?
我可以進去了嗎？
-Why is everything different? -Bye.
為什麼東西都變了？ 再見
I don't see anything different...
沒有變啊
other than the fact that the room got brighter when you came into it.
只不過你一進來 房裡變得更亮了
The end table is wrong, the couch looks bizarre...
小茶几位置不對 沙發怪怪的
and don't even get me started on the refrigerator magnets.
更別提冰箱上的磁鐵
Okay,don't be mad, okay?
你別生氣
After I unpacked the boxes,I wanted to do something nice for you...
我整理完東西 想做點讓你高興的事
so I cleaned the apartment.
所以我就大掃除
So I moved everything around, and then I forgot...
我把東西亂搬 卻忘了...
where it went back. I'm sorry,I'm very sorry,I'm sorry.
該怎麼復原  對不起 對不起 對不起
That's okay.
沒關係 錢德
Are you afraid of me or something?
你在怕我嗎？
Do you want me to be afraid of you?
你要我怕你嗎？
Of course not.
當然不要
My gosh, Chandler,what you did is a wonderful thing...
拜託，你做了這麼棒的事
and I really appreciate it.
我真的很開心
I have this thing where I want everything in the perfect place.
我知道我對東西的擺設有怪癖
But I'd never expect you to worry about that.
但我萬萬沒想到你會擔心
Really?
真的？
Of course.
當然是真的
Oh,you're the best.
你最好了
You come here to me.
過來我抱抱
Hold on, okay? First things first.
等等，先做該做的事
Did Ross sit anywhere while he was naked?
羅斯光著身體時坐過哪裡？
It said that by the year 2030...
書上說到了2030年
there'll be computers carrying out the same number of functions...
有些電腦 能執行...
as an actual human brain.
跟人腦一樣多的功能
So, theoretically, you could download your thoughts...
所以理論上人可以下載你的思想...
and your memories into this computer..
和記憶到這種電腦上
And live forever as a machine.
然後以機器的形態長生不死
Janine,do you know what we're doing right now?
你知道我們現在在做什麼嗎？
You and I,we're interfacing.
我們在連結
I gotta go.
我該走了